usdirect.com 2011-10-06

# Privacy Policy

USDIRECT is dedicated to protecting consumer privacy. This Privacy Policy explains how USDIRECT collects, uses, and discloses information about you when you subscribe to DIRECTV's digital satellite television programming services and when you visit our Web site(s). Your use or receipt of USDIRECT� products or services (including our Web site(s)) constitutes acceptance of this Privacy Policy. 

This Privacy Policy provides information about our practices in the following areas: 

  1. The nature of the personally identifiable information we collect about you and the way such information is used.
  2. The nature, frequency, and purpose of any disclosure of personally identifiable information that we may make, including the types of persons or entities to whom the disclosure may be made.
  3. The period of time for which we maintain personally identifiable information.
  4. How you may obtain access to and correct any personally identifiable information about you.

**I. Types of Customer Information that we collect and how we collect it.**

In discussing the types of information that we collect from subscribers and visitors to our Web site(s), it is important to distinguish between two categories of information. We use "Customer Information" as a broad, general term that refers to any information relating to you or your DIRECTV service, including Account Information, Service Information, Anonymous Viewing Information, Diagnostic Information, Commerce Information, and Web Site Information. These terms are defined in more detail below in Section A. 

We use the term "Personally Identifiable Viewing Information" to refer to information about your personal viewing habits that we collect only with your express consent. This term is defined in more detail below in Section B. 

A. The following are specific types of Customer Information that we collect from customers and visitors to our Web site(s): 

"Account Information" means information about your DIRECTV service account, including your name, address, social security number, e-mail address, telephone number, what programming packages you subscribe to, consumer credit reports, the model and serial number of your DIRECTV Receiver, software version used, and privacy preferences. Account Information does not include any Personally Identifiable Viewing Information or Anonymous Viewing Information, as defined below. We collect Account Information directly from you when you activate or change your service, as well as from third parties, such as consumer reporting agencies. 

"Service Information" means information necessary for us to provide service to your DIRECTV Receiver. Examples of Service Information include your receiver's software version number and the success status of the last attempted service call by your receiver. 

"Commerce Information" means personally identifiable information that enables a commerce partner to fulfill your request to participate in a promotion or transaction. From time to time, we may present special offers or enable you to purchase goods and services from us or third party advertisers or promoters. You would be informed of such offers on screen. Should you decide to take advantage of such an offer or engage in a transaction, we will collect and communicate information such as your name and address and your interest in a specific offer or transaction to the commerce partner sponsoring the promotion or transaction. This information is collected and disclosed by us only after you elect to participate in an offer. In addition to fulfilling your request, that commerce partner may also use your Commerce Information to send you other information in which you might be interested consistent with its own privacy policies. 

"Web Site Information" means information that is collected and stored in our secure computing environment when you become a registered user of, or visit, our Web site(s). Information about visitors to our Web site(s) and the e-mail address of people who write to us are stored in our secure computing environment, which includes industry-standard authentication technologies. If you are a visitor to our Web site(s), we may collect information that you provide us (including your e-mail address) and use it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Whether or not you are a USDIRECT customer, we may collect information about visitors to our Web site(s) as follows: 

Cookies: We use cookies to our Web site(s) for returning visitors. These cookies remain on your computer and are automatically retrieved when you visit our Web site(s) at a later time. These cookies contain only information concerning the type of customer and frequently visited pages. No other Customer Information is stored on cookies. 

If you are uncomfortable with the use of cookies, you may disable them on your computer. Please be advised that disabling cookies may affect user functionality but the design of the USDIRECT Web site(s) generally allow access to most offerings for users who have disabled cookies. 

Aggregate information about Web site visitors: We create aggregate reports of visitors to our Web site(s) in order to measure the performance of our Web site(s). These reports do not contain any Customer Information about visitors to our Web site(s). 

Links to other Web sites: When you visit our Web site(s), you may find opportunities to link to Web sites of third parties. When you click through to these sites, USDIRECT's Privacy Policy no longer applies. We recommend that you read the privacy policy for any third party Web sites. 

**II. Use of Customer Information**

We use Customer Information to deliver our service to our customers and to understand what our customers want so that we can continue to provide a compelling entertainment service at a good value. Specifically, we use Customer Information for editorial and feedback purposes, for marketing and promotional purposes, for statistical analysis, for product development and content improvement, to verify customer qualifications to receive our service, and for other related business purposes. 

**III. When we share Customer Information with Third Parties We share Customer Information with companies and other third parties where necessary to conduct a legitimate business activity related to providing service to our customers, including as follows:**

Third party services: We share Customer Information with third parties in order to coordinate delivery or billing of the services provided by such third parties to your DIRECTV Receiver. We take reasonable steps to require these third parties to maintain the confidentiality of the Customer Information and require them to adhere to this Privacy Policy. 

Affiliated companies: We may share Customer Information with affiliated companies of USDIRECT. If we choose to share data in this fashion, we will require our affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy. 

Marketing: We may share Customer Information, including programming purchases, with selected media, entertainment, and other similar service providers. These service providers may use this Customer Information to market products or services to you. We may disclose aggregated Anonymous Viewing Information and any reports or analyses derived therefrom, to third parties including suppliers, advertisers, broadcasters, consumer and market research companies and other organizations. 

Legal requirements: We may share Customer Information with third parties in order to meet legal requirements or as otherwise specifically permitted by law. Under the Communications Act, we may be required to disclose Customer Information and Personally Identifiable Viewing Information in response to a court order. If such an order is sought by a government entity, the law requires that you be provided notice and the opportunity to control the order in a court proceeding. 

Sale or transfer of the business: We may share Customer Information with third parties in connection with the sale, transfer, or other assignment of our business. If we are acquired by another company, that company will possess the Customer Information collected by us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Customer Information as described in this Privacy Policy. 

**V. How long we keep Customer Information**

We maintain information about you for as long as we provide service to you, and for a longer time if necessary for related business activities. When information is no longer necessary for our business purposes, we will destroy the information unless there is an outstanding request or order to inspect the information. 

**VII. Steps we take to protect the security of Customer Information**

We take reasonable steps to protect Customer Information by using industry-standard security technologies and internal procedures that limit access to our databases. However, no system is completely secure or error-free. We do not, and cannot, guarantee the complete security or accuracy of Customer Information. If you feel we have incorrect information, please contact us. 

**VIII. Online credit card transactions**

We protect the security of credit card transactions on the Internet by using a secure, encrypted Web server. We maintain credit card information collected during transactions in a secure database at USDIRECT for fraud prevention and accounting and billing purposes. Your credit card information is not available to unauthorized parties while in these databases. Stored information from credit card transactions is not released to third parties except in response to a subpoena or court order. 

**X. Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make a significant change with regard to our collection or use of information about our customers, we will note on the main page of our Web site(s) that this Privacy Policy has been updated.

The Effective Date hereto shall be June 01, 2009.
